export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    questionText:
      'Which medieval castle in Stockholm is considered one of the most well-preserved castles in Sweden?',
    options: [
      'Kalmar Castle',
      'Vadstena Castle',
      'Örebro Castle',
      'Stockholm Palace',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    questionText:
      "Who is the Swedish author known for the Millennium series, including 'The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo'?",
    options: [
      'Henning Mankell',
      'Stieg Larsson',
      'Camilla Läckberg',
      'Jo Nesbø',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    questionText: 'In what year did Sweden join the European Union?',
    options: ['1995', '2000', '2004', '2008', 'not answered'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    questionText:
      'Which Swedish company is a leading provider of mobile communication technology?',
    options: ['Volvo', 'Ericsson', 'H&M', 'IKEA', 'not answered'],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    questionText:
      'What is the traditional Swedish dish made of pickled herring, potatoes, and sour cream?',
    options: [
      'Gravlax',
      'Köttbullar',
      'Surströmming',
      'Sill och potatis',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    questionText:
      'Sweden is located on the Scandinavian Peninsula in Northern Europe and shares land borders with which two countries?',
    options: [
      'Norway and Finland',
      'Denmark and Finland',
      'Norway and Denmark',
      'Norway and Russia',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    questionText:
      'Which Swedish scientist is known as the father of modern taxonomy and binomial nomenclature?',
    options: [
      'Carl von Linné',
      'Alfred Nobel',
      'Anders Celsius',
      'Gustav Dalén',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    questionText: 'What is the famous ice hotel located in Sweden called?',
    options: [
      'Frosty Lodge',
      'Glacier Palace',
      'Ice Kingdom',
      'ICEHOTEL',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    questionText:
      "Which event is celebrated on June 6th and is considered Sweden's National Day?",
    options: [
      "Midsummer's Day",
      'Christmas',
      'Independence Day',
      'Constitution Day',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    questionText:
      'What is the name of the Swedish traditional celebration involving a maypole, flowers, and dancing around the pole?',
    options: [
      'Walpurgis Night',
      'Midsommar',
      'Lucia Day',
      'Valborgsmässoafton',
      'not answered',
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  },
];
